Guide to the Paris Montoya Collection of Air Raid Recordings MC.412
New York University Archives
Paris Montoya Collection of Air Raid Recordings
mid 1990s
New York University Archives
Montoya, Paris
NYU-TV
MC.412
2 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 tall manuscript box
5 VHS
29 Betacam_SP
1 U-matic
Paris Montoya is a marketing director and NYU alumnus. He was one of the student producers of Air Raid, the first student-produced show to air on NYU-TV in the mid-1990s. At the time, students involved with the station brainstormed ideas for shows and identified people to make them through tabling at the annual student club fair and through classes at the Tisch School of the Arts. Funding for the show production was allocated by NYU Libraries, of which NYU-TV was and continues to administratively be part of, with the exception of specials, for which additional funding was secured through Student Affairs. Specials aired at the beginning of each semester. Although students typically worked with new stock, during production students used any tape accessible to them. The Paris Montoya Collection of Air Raid Recordings (dated mid 1990s) consists of analog video recordings of the student-produced music video, concert, and interview show Air Raid.
Scope and Contents
The Paris Montoya Collection of Air Raid Recordings (dated mid 1990s) consists of analog video recordings of the student-produced music video, concert, and interview show Air Raid. Episodes for which no original recordings are present in this collection or the Records of NYU TV and Media Services (RG 38.16.1) likely do not exist.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged primarily in chronological order, the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Paris Montoya in November 2024; the accession number associated with this gift is 2024.079.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact New York University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Biographical Note
Paris Montoya is a marketing director and NYU alumnus. He was one of the student producers of Air Raid, the first student-produced show to air on NYU-TV in the mid-1990s.
Historical Note
Air Raid was the first student-produced show to air on NYU-TV in the mid-1990s. At the time, students involved with the station brainstormed ideas for shows and identified people to make them through tabling at the annual student club fair and through classes at the Tisch School of the Arts. Funding for the show production was allocated by NYU Libraries, of which NYU-TV was and continues to administratively be part of, with the exception of specials, for which additional funding was secured through Student Affairs. Specials aired at the beginning of each semester. Although students typically worked with new stock, during production students used any tape accessible to them.
Television programs.; Television broadcasting.; Student activities.; Television -- Production and direction; Montoya, Paris
- Air Raid Episode 4, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0001)
- Air Raid Episode 5, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0002)
- Air Raid Episode 12, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0003)
- Air Raid Episode 13, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0004)
- Air Raid Episode 14, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0005)
- Air Raid Episode 15, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0006)
- Air Raid Episode 16, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0007)
- Air Raid Episode 17, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0008)
- Air Raid Episode 18, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0009)
- Air Raid Episode 19, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0010)
- Air Raid Episode 20, mid 1990s (Box 1, Betacam sp 412.0011)
- Air Raid Episode 21, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0012)
- Air Raid Episode 22, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0013)
- Air Raid Episode 23, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0014)
- Air Raid Episode 24, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0015)
- Air Raid Episode 25, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0016)
- Air Raid Episode 26, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0017)
- Air Raid Episode 27, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0018)
- Air Raid Episode 28, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0019)
- Air Raid Episode 29, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0020)
- Air Raid Episode 30, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0021)
- Air Raid Episode 31, mid 1990s (Box 2, Betacam sp 412.0022)
- Air Raid Episode 32, mid 1990s (Box 3, Betacam sp 412.0023)
- Spork Special, mid 1990s (Box 4, Betacam sp 412.0024)
- Sound Advice Special, mid 1990s
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Betacam sp 412.0025)
  - VHS Recording (Box 3, Vhs 412.0026)
- Agent 99 Special, mid 1990s (Box 4, Betacam sp 412.0027)
- Mama Kettle Special, mid 1990s
  - Original Recording (Box 4, Betacam sp 412.0028)
  - VHS Recording (Box 3, Vhs 412.0029)
- Native Strangers Special, mid 1990s
  - Original Recording (Box 4, U-matic 412.0030)
  - VHS Recording (Box 3, Vhs 412.0031)
- Air Raid Promos, mid 1990s (Box 3, Betacam sp 412.0032)
- Dyneomatic, Agent 99, King Af Raw Interviews -- Tape 1, mid 1990s (Box 4, Betacam sp 412.0033)
- Air Raid Promo TV Club 1 -- Rooftops and Night, 1994-08-02 (Box 3, Vhs 412.0034)
- Air Raid Promo TV Club 2, 1994-08-02 (Box 3, Vhs 412.0035)